A Guide to the Papers of Collins Denny 1872-1943
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Collins Denny Papers: Articles and Speeches
  - Response to Welcome Address on return to Virginia [1912?] (Box-folder 67:21)
  - Eulogy on John P. Branch 1915 February (Box-folder 67:22)
  - Notes and Drafts 1915 (Box-folder 67:23)
    Dissenting opinion in College of Bishops
  - Eulogy on Bishop Alpheus Wilson 1916 November (Box-folder 67:24)
  - Article "Politics in the Methodist Episcopal Church, South" 1917 January (Box-folder 67:25)
  - Confederate Reunion Address 1917 June (Box-folder 67:26)
  - Address at the Memorial service at Arlington 1917 November (Box-folder 67:27)
  - Minority Report of the Committee on the Status of the Negro [1917?] (Box-folder 67:28)
  - "Bishop and Mrs. Elijah Hoss: An Appreciation" and "Bishop Elijah Embree Hoss: An Editorial" 1915- 1919 (Box-folder 67:29)
  - Methodism Reorganized 1920 April (Box-folder 67:30)
  - Article on Unification 1920 March (Box-folder 67:31)
  - Article, Article II on Unification 1920 April (Box-folder 67:32)
  - Article, Article III on Unification 1920 April & May (Box-folder 67:33)
  - Minority Report of the Commission appointed to consider the Unification of the Methodist Epsicopal Church, South and the Methodist Episcopal Church 67:34 (Box-folder 67:34)
  - Notes for Minortity Report of Commission on Unification 1924 (Box-folder 67:35)
  - [Article?] "Is Educated Ministry Necessary" 1920 August (Box-folder 67:36)
  - [Article ?] "The Effort to Secure Efficient Preachers" 1920 August (Box-folder 67:37)
  - Speech "A Review of the Existing Situation" [192?] (Box-folder 68:1)
  - Some objections to the proposed plan of Methodist Unification [192?] (Box-folder 68:2)
  - Ashbury Speech 1921 October (Box-folder 68:3)
  - Articles "Report of the Commission on the Constitution of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South" 1921 (Box-folder 68:4)
  - Article "Protecting Arms" 1922 February (Box-folder 68:5)
  - Article "Has Our Commission Found Our Constitution?" 1922 May (Box-folder 68:6)
  - [Article?] "The Heroism of the Methodist Preacher" 1923 February (Box-folder 68:7)
  - Article "How is Legal Title Determined?" 1923 September (Box-folder 68:8)
  - Pamphlet "Is the De Facto 1924 Session of the General Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South, De Jure?" 1924 June (Box-folder 68:9)
  - "John Albames Bengeluis" [1924?] (Box-folder 68:10)
  - Episcopal Address [1924?] (Box-folder 68:11)
  - Notes on Episcopal Address [1924, 1926? & n.d.) (Box-folder 68:12)
  - Episcopal Address, Memphis, Tenn. 1926 May (Box-folder 68:13)
  - [Article] Untitled 1927 December (Box-folder 68:14)
  - Statement on the Church on Politics, and Speech in the U. S. House by Hon. Cole L. Blease on Denny Speech 1928 and 1929 October. (Box-folder 68:15)
  - Article "The Latest and Greatest Christian Conflict for Faith" 1928 February (Box-folder 68:16)
  - Review of J. G. Machen's The Virgin Birth of Christ1930 April 4 (Box-folder 68:17)
  - Article "The Judicial Council, Is It Wise To Adopt It?" 1931 July (Box-folder 68:18)
  - Article "The Proposed Judicial Council" 1931 September 11 (Box-folder 68:19)
  - Notes on Judicial Council Articles 1934 (Box-folder 68:20)
  - Prayer at Yorktown 1931 October & 1932 October (Box-folder 68:21)
  - Prayer at the Unveiling of the Lee Statue, Capital Building, Richmond, Virginia 1932 January (Box-folder 68:22)
  - Article "Once More Unto the Breach" 1932 July (Box-folder 68:23)
  - Denny's Preface to 17th Edition of the "Manual of Discipline" [1932?] (Box-folder 68:24)
  - Article "How to Be A Useful Methodist Preacher" 1934 February (Box-folder 68:25)
  - Letter "An Appeal to Men of Reason and Religion Concerning Methodist Unification" 1937 August (Box-folder 68:26)
  - Article "A Reply to Dr. Garber" [1937?] (Box-folder 68:28)
  - Letter to Editor [of Southern Methodist Layman] [1937 or 1938] (Box-folder 68:29)
  - Letter to the Uniting Conference of the Methodist Church 1939 May (Box-folder 68:30)
  - Preface to the 19th Edition of Manual of Disciplinen.d. (Box-folder 69:1)
  - Episcopal Address n.d. (Box-folder 69:2)
  - Speech n.d. (Box-folder 69:3)
  - Article "Subordinate Means to End" n.d. (Box-folder 69:4)
  - [Speech] on Episcopacy of Church Constitution n.d. (Box-folder 69:5)
  - Pamphlet "Historic and Heroic Acts of The Old Baltimore Conference" n.d. (Box-folder 69:6)
  - Introduction to Dr. Cunningham's People History of the Chinesen.d. (Box-folder 69:7)
  - Prayer at Unveiling of bust of James Madison n.d. (Box-folder 69:8)
  - Acceptance Speech, Randolph Macon College n.d. (Box-folder 69:9)
  - Address, "Duty" to a graduating class n.d. (Box-folder 69:10)
  - Address, Wesleyan Female Institute n.d. (Box-folder 69:11)
  - Notes for Round Table Discussion "The English Occupation of Egypt" n.d. (Box-folder 69:12)
  - Notes for Round Table Discussion "The Acropolis at Athens" n.d. (Box-folder 69:13)
  - Notes on Vanderbilt Alumni Address n.d. (Box-folder 69:14)
  - Address, S. S. Convention at Clifton Forge; "The Child in the Heart of Jesus" n.d. (Box-folder 69:15)
  - [Article] "Jacob's Well" n.d. (Box-folder 69:16)
  - [Article?] "The Geography of the Bible" n.d. (Box-folder 69:17)
  - [Article?] "Palestine in the Time of Christ" n.d. (Box-folder 69:18)
  - Article "Geography in Bible Hands" n.d. (Box-folder 69:19)
  - [Article?] "The Psalms" n.d. (Box-folder 69:20)
  - [Speech notes?] "The Preacher in His Study" n.d. (Box-folder 69:21)
  - Eulogy on Dr. W. H. Morgan n.d. (Box-folder 69:22)
  - Article "Care of Superannuate Preachers" n.d. (Box-folder 69:23)
  - Article, "Frank M. Thomas" n.d. (Box-folder 69:24)
  - Article "Bishop Whatcoat" n.d. (Box-folder 69:25)
  - Eulogy on Rev. James Monroe Mason, D. D. n.d. (Box-folder 69:26)
  - Walter Russell Lambuth? n.d. (Box-folder 69:27)
  - "Patrick Henry: The Orator, The Statesman, The Man" n.d. (Box-folder 69:28)
  - "Diary of John Early, Bishop of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South" n.d. (Box-folder 69:29)
  - "Oliver Cromwell" n.d. (Box-folder 69:30)
  - "John Chalmers" n.d. (Box-folder 69:31)
  - [Article?] On The Richmond Christian Advocaten.d. (Box-folder 69:32)
  - "The Standing Still of the Sun Upon Gideon" n.d. (Box-folder 69:33)
  - Article, "The Place of the Child in Modern Life" n.d. (Box-folder 69:34)
  - Article "The Books which interested and helped me before my Fifteenth year" n.d. (Box-folder 69:35)
  - Letter to Bishop [Evanston] on the invasion of Southern Methodist territory n.d. (Box-folder 69:36)
  - Fifty years of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South n.d. (Box-folder 69:37)
  - Article, "Administration of Discipline" n.d. (Box-folder 69:38)
  - Article "A Visit to Chicago and Cornell" n.d. (Box-folder 69:39)
  - Notes on The Judicial Council n.d. (Box-folder 69:40)
  - Notes on changing the name of the Church n.d. (Box-folder 69:41)
  - Notes on Constitution of the Church and Unification n.d. (Box-folder 69:42)
  - Notes on the importance of Sunday Schools n.d. (Box-folder 69:43)
  - Resolutions of the Book Committee on the death of John B. Ransom n.d. (Box-folder 69:44)
  - Publication of the Official Call of the Special Session of the General Conference n.d. (Box-folder 69:45)
  - Minutes of the Baltimore Annual Conference n.d. (Box-folder 69:46)
  - "The Negro Problem" n.d. (Box-folder 69:47)
  - New America: Its Policy of Expansion n.d. (Box-folder 69:48)
  - "The South's Part in the History of the American Republic" n.d. (Box-folder 69:49)
  - "Pro Patria" n.d. (Box-folder 69:50)
  - To the Editor of Richmond Times-Dispatch; "Inquisitions-Ancient and Modern" n.d. (Box-folder 69:51)
  - "... .in passing under review the work of the last year.. .." n.d. (Box-folder 69:52)
  - Minutes of several meetings of the Board of Directors of the Methodist Publishing House in China and Reports of the Board to the Book Committee of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South ca. 1903 (Box-folder 70:1)
  - Minutes of Methodist Episcopal Church, South Book Committee Meetings 1902 & 1903 (Box-folder 70:2)
  - Notebook n.d. (Box-folder 70:3)
    containing sermon drafts and an "analysis of the epistle to the Romans"
  - Untitled sermon n.d. (Box-folder 70:4)
    re: "Standards of Doctrine"
  - Report of the "General Superintendents of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South n.d. (Box-folder 70:5)
  - "The Conference of 1779" n.d., Handwritten draft (Box-folder 70:6)
  - Miscellaneous articles collected and hand copied by Denny n.d. (Box-folder 70:7)
  - Notes from Southwest Missouri Conference Meeting September 14-19 (Box-folder 70:8)
  - "Claim of the Publishing House of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South against the U. S. Government" n.d. (Box-folder 70:9)
  - Denny drafts of articles and reports n.d. (Box-folder 70:10)
    re: Publishing House, Methodist Episcopal Church, South vs. U. S. Government
  - Decision given at the Kentucky Conference 1919 September 6 (Box-folder 70:11)
  - Untitled draft of report on the demand for the resignation of the Book Committee n.d. (Box-folder 70:12)
  - Notes and drafts for speeches and articles n.d. (Box-folder 70:13)
- Collins Denny: Sermons and Sermon Notes
  - Record of Sermons 1880-1938 (Box-folder 71:1)
  - Published Sermon "His Name Was Jesus" 1895 December (Box-folder 71:2)
  - Sermon Notes "Hear and Your Soul Shall Live" 1901 August (Box-folder 71:3)
  - Sermon given at Richmond, Virginia; "The Validity of Christian Experience" 1902 January (Box-folder 71:4)
  - Notes taken of the sermon delivered by Dr. Denny; "Worship God" 1905 July (Box-folder 71:5)
  - Notes at University of Virginia; "David, a man after mine own heart" 1911 December (Box-folder 71:6)
  - Sermon at North Ala. Conference in Sylacauga; "I am debtor both to the Greek and the Barbarians" 1914 November (Box-folder 71:7)
  - Published Sermon; "Mary Magdalene... The Power of Love" 1915 August (Box-folder 71:8)
  - Sermon "Wesley and the English People" or "The Moral Conditions of the English People at the Rise of Methodism [1922?] (Box-folder 71:9)
  - Published Sermon "The Forgiveness of Sins" 1926 May (Box-folder 71:10)
  - Published Sermon "Who is God?" given at Baltimore Conference, Staunton, Virginia 1928 September (Box-folder 71:11)
  - Semi-Centenial Sermon given at Baltimore Conference 1929 September (Box-folder 71:12)
  - Notes "Galatians 6:10" n.d. (Box-folder 71:13)
  - Notes "Wisdom of Solomon, 4:7-14" n.d. (Box-folder 71:14)
  - Sermon Notes Exodus 33:18 and Phil. 3:10 n.d. (Box-folder 71:15)
  - Sermon "The Atoning Power of Christ's Blood" given in Nashville n.d. (Box-folder 71:16)
  - Early Sermon Notes n.d. (Box-folder 71:18)
  - Miscellaneous Notes on Speeches and Sermons n.d. (Box-folder 71:19)
- Collins Denny: Personal documents, certificates, and items useful for biographical purposes
  - Coin collection list 1872 February (Box-folder 72:1)
  - Financial receipts and notes 1872-1904 (Box-folder 72:2)
  - Petition of Bankruptcy of John E. Massie 1872 September 24 (Box-folder 72:3)
  - Football Certificate 1873 (Box-folder 72:4)
  - Athletic participation 1873 November and 1875 June (Box-folder 72:5)
  - Senior Orations Programs 1875 December (Box-folder 72:6)
  - Graduation Orations Program 1876 June (Box-folder 72:7)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Certificate 1902 June (Box-folder 72:8)
  - Briefs and Testimony, Faurst vs. Winchester Paper Co.1879 (Box-folder 72:9)
  - Briefs and Testimony, F aurst vs. Winchester Paper Co. 1879 (Box-folder 72:10)
  - Law business 1877 (Box-folder 72:11)
  - Passport 1880, 1887 (Box-folder 72:12)
  - Protest against vice at Fincastle Fair 1882 (Box-folder 72:13)
  - Tithing records of charges 1884, 1895 (Box-folder 72:14)
  - Receipts from trip around the world 1886, 1887 (Box-folder 72:15)
  - Reports from classes at University of Virginia 1890- 1891 (Box-folder 72:16)
  - Fraternity material 1893- 1894 (Box-folder 72:17)
  - Contract to preach 1897 (Box-folder 72:18)
  - By Laws of Methodist Publishing House in China 1902 (Box-folder 72:19)
  - Testimony of A. F. Mayne in land suit 1902 June (Box-folder 72:20)
  - Account book as Executor of William R. Denny Estate 1904- 1908 (Box-folder 72:21)
  - Last Will and Testament 1906 (Box-folder 72:22)
  - Reports from McKendree Methodist Episcopal Church, South and Clarksville, Tenn. 1906 and 1907 (Box-folder 72:23)
  - Certificate to Elder's membership 1909 July (Box-folder 72:24)
  - Marriage Certificate 1909 August (Box-folder 72:25)
  - President's Annual Report; Virginia Bridge and Iron Co. 1912 (Box-folder 72:26)
  - Petition 1915 October and November (Box-folder 72:27)
    re: Richmond mass meeting about Police Commissioners
  - Certificate of ordination for Marvin Augustus Franklin 1915 November (Box-folder 72:28)
  - Minutes and notes on Pacific Mexican Mission 1917 March (Box-folder 72:29)
  - Commission as Honorary Delegate to Atlantic Congress for a League of Nations 1919 January 22 (Box-folder 72:29-a)
  - Member Certificate; Virginia War History Commission 1919 January (Box-folder 72;30)
  - University of Virginia Baccalaureate Program 1924 (Box-folder 72:31)
  - Certificate of Appointment as Delegate to the Conference on Higher Education 1927 January (Box-folder 72:32)
  - Health and Lab Examinations 1897, 1937 (Box-folder 72:33)
  - Program 1938 (Box-folder 72:34)
  - Epitaph and Eulogy for Lucy Chase Chapman Denny 1940 (Box-folder 72:35)
  - Expenses on the Mexican Trip n.d. (Box-folder 72:36)
  - Certificate as Delegate to International Sunday School Conference n.d. (Box-folder 72:37)
  - Membership Cards 1907, 1926, and n.d. (Box-folder 72:38)
  - Biographical Sketch of Collins Denny n.d. (Box-folder 72:39)
  - Miscellaneous accounts statements ca. 1890 (Box-folder 72:40)
- Collins Denny: Notes- academic and on church history
  - Princeton Lecture Notes 1876 (Box-folder 73:1)
  - Princeton Lecture Notes 1876 (Box-folder 73:2)
  - Princeton Lecture Notes 1876 (Box-folder 73:3)
  - Princeton Lecture Notes 1876 (Box-folder 73:4)
  - Law Notes n.d. (Box-folder 73:5)
  - Notes on Davis's Ethics n.d. (Box-folder 73:6)
  - Notes and materials on Noah K. Davis n.d. (Box-folder 73:7)
  - Notes; The Natural History of Morals n.d. (Box-folder 73:8)
  - Analysis of Lotze's Practical Philosophy n.d. (Box-folder 73:9)
  - Analysis of Davis' Inductive Logic n.d. (Box-folder 73:10)
  - Lecture Notes, "Uherden Ursprung der Sprache" n.d. (Box-folder 73:11)
  - Logic Notes n.d. (Box-folder 73:12)
  - Collins Denny Scrapbook; 3 Denny notebooks on Noah K. Davis n.d. (Box 74)
  - Examination questions at Vanderbilt University 1890-1909 (Box-folder 75:1)
  - Examination questions at Vanderbilt University n.d. (Box-folder 75:2)
  - Notes from William Gurney's The History of Episcopacyn.d. (Box-folder 75:3)
  - Questions on Watson's Institutes, with the answers n.d. (Box-folder 75:4)
  - Miscellaneous notes found in 1925 Manuel of the Discipline1925 (Box-folder 75:5)
  - Miscellaneous notes found in Stevens History of Methodismn.d. (Box-folder 75:6)
  - Notes of Authors in Bledsoe's Review- The Southern Reviewn.d. (Box-folder 75:7)
  - Anecdote: An unusual wedding n.d. (Box-folder 75:8)
  - Miscellaneous notes n.d. (Box-folder 75:9)
- Collins Denny and Church matters: Clippings
  - News Clippings 1880 and 1890 (Box-folder 76:1)
  - Articles by Bishop A. W. Wilson on Trip Around the World 1887 (Box-folder 76:2)
  - News Clippings on Denny 1900-1906 (Box-folder 76:3)
  - News Clippings 1911 (Box-folder 76:4)
    re: Move to Richmond, Virginia
  - News Clippings on Denny 1908-1912 (Box-folder 76:5)
  - News Clippings on Denny 1913- 1914 (Box-folder 76:6)
  - News Clippings on Denny 1915- 1916 (Box-folder 76:7)
  - News Clippings on Denny 1917- 1919 (Box-folder 76:8)
  - News Clippings on Denny 1920-1924 (Box-folder 76:9)
  - News Clippings on Denny 1925- 1927 (Box-folder 76:10)
  - News Clippings on Denny 1928-1930 (Box-folder 76:11)
  - Denny on Prohibition 1933 (Box-folder 76:12)
  - News Clippping on Denny and Unification 1924-1925 (Box-folder 76:13)
  - News Clippings on Denny, Denny, Jr. and Unification 1937-1939 (Box-folder 76:14)
  - News Clippings on Denny, Denny, Jr. at Unification 1937-1939 (Box-folder 76:15)
  - News Clippings on Denny n.d. (Box-folder 76:16)
  - News Clippings--Church matters n.d. (Box-folder 76:17)
  - Princeton vs. Rutgers 1875 (Box-folder 76:18)
  - re: Methodist Doctrine, 1st Restrictive Rule 1889 (Box-folder 76:19)
  - The Book Committee and Dr. Steel 1896 (Box-folder 76:20)
  - re: Maryland and Winchester Methodism 1897-1926 (Box-folder 76:21)
  - re: Bishop A. W. Wilson 1889-1919 (Box-folder 76:22)
  - re: General Conference and Publishing House 1902 (Box-folder 76:23)
  - Gustan Abraham's "Methodism in the Southern States" 1906 (Box-folder 77:1)
  - Article by H. J. Lamar 1907 (Box-folder 77:2)
  - Articles on various Bishops 1912, 1922, 1923, 1924, and n.d. (Box-folder 77:3)
  - Barnes Hospital 1912 (Box-folder 77:4)
  - re: Vanderbilt University 1912, 1913, 1918, and n.d. (Box-folder 77:5)
  - re: The Knott Case 1915 (Box-folder 77:6)
  - Laymen vs. Power of Bishops 1917- 1921 (Box-folder 77:7)
  - "What Negroes are Doing" by Oscar W. Adams 1920 May 2 (Box-folder 77:8)
  - Articles by various Bishops 1922 (Box-folder 77:9)
    re: "Report of Commission on the Constitution of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South"
  - J. J. Ransom's "Revision of the 23rd. Article of Religion" 1922 (Box-folder 77:10)
  - John T. Ellison's "The Third Restrictive Rule" 1921 (Box-folder 77:11)
  - re: 4th. Street Church, Louisville, Ky. 1922 (Box-folder 77:12)
  - re: Standards of Doctrine Changes 1926 (Box-folder 77:13)
  - re: Virginia Conference; "Politics and Moral Standards" 1929 (Box-folder 77:14)
  - Church matters; The Cannon Case 1930-1932 (Box-folder 77:14)
  - Church matters; The Cannon Case 1930-1932 (Box-folder 77:15)
  - re: Unification 1919-1925 (Box-folder 77:16)
  - Clipping of First Protestant Church of Washington and K. K. K. 1937 October (Box-folder 77:17)
  - Methodist Unification 1938-1939 (Box-folder 77:18)
  - On Unification 1937-1939 (Box-folder 77:19)
  - Religious Periodicals on Unification 1937-1939 (Box-folder 77:20)
  - Religious Periodicals on Unification 1938-1939 (Box-folder 77:21)
  - "Dr. John H. Rice and His Books.. ." by E. D. Morgan n.d. (Box-folder 77:22)
  - Miscellaneous Editorials n.d. (Box-folder 77:23)
  - Miscellaneous Letters to Editor n.d. (Box-folder 77:24)
  - re: Various Correspondents n.d. (Box-folder 77:25)
  - Items of historical or literary interest n.d. (Box-folder 77:26)
  - Miscellaneous n.d. (Box-folder 77:27)
  - Clippings; Unification 1909-1923 (Box-folder 78:1)
  - Clippings 1924 (Box-folder 78:2)
  - Clippings 1924 (Box-folder 78:3)
  - A resume of the proceedings of the Joint Commission on Unification of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South and the Methodist Episcopal Church at St. Louis 1918 April 10-13 (Box-folder 78:4)
  - A resume of the proceedings of the Joint Commission of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South and the Methodist Episcopal Church at Savannah, Ga. 1918 January 23-1918 February 6 (Box-folder 78:5)
  - Minutes of the Joint Commission on Unification of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South and the Methodist Episcopal Church at Louisville, Ky. 1920 January 15- 20 (Box-folder 78:6)
  - Miscellaneous reports and articles on Unification n.d. (Box-folder 78:7)
  - Clippings ca. 1926-ca. 1930 (Box-folder 79:1)
    re: Church matters--Bishop Cannon
  - Clippings ca. 1926-ca. 1930 (Box-folder 79:2)
  - Clippings ca. 1926-ca. 1930 (Box-folder 79:3)
  - Clippings ca. 1929 (Box-folder 79:4)
  - Clippings 1925 (Box-folder 80:1)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings n.d. (Box-folder 80:2)
  - Clippings 1894-1910 (Box-folder 80:3)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings 1870-1880 (Box-folder 80:4)
  - Clippings n.d. (Box-folder 80:5)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings n.d. (Box-folder 80:6)
- Collins Denny: Memorabilia
  - Laws of College of New Jersey 1870 (Box-folder 81:1)
  - Princeton Magazines and Programs 1874-1876 (Box-folder 81:2)
  - Princeton Class Roll 1876 (Box-folder 81:3)
  - Cook's Tour 1880 and 1886-1887 (Box-folder 81:4)
  - Programs and Literature; University of Virginia 1890 (Box-folder 81:5)
  - Invitations to William Taft Breakfast 1911 September (Box-folder 81:6)
  - Announcement of Princeton reunion 1911 May 12 (Box-folder 81:7)
  - Invitation to welcome Woodrow Wilson to Staunton, Virginia 1912 (Box-folder 81:8)
  - Tribute to A. W. Wilson 1914 and 1919 (Box-folder 81:9)
  - Official Souvenir, 25th Reunion United Confederate Veterans 1915 June (Box-folder 81:10)
  - Ceremonies at Virginia Memorial, Gettysburg, Virginia 1917 June (Box-folder 81:11)
  - Invitation to Interchurch World Movement of North America 81:12 (Box-folder 81:12)
  - Address delivered at the Opening of the Building of the Confederate Memorial Institute 1921 May (Box-folder 81:13)
  - Commencement Program, University of Virginia; Student Handbook, University of Virginia; Student Handbook, Vanderbilt 1924; 1890-1891; 1894-1895 (Box-folder 81:14)
  - Program at the Unveiling of Robert E. Lee Statue, Stone Mountain 1928 (Box-folder 81:15)
  - Invitation from Woodrow Wilson n.d. (Box-folder 81:16)
  - Miscellaneous Invitations n.d. (Box-folder 81:17)
  - Photographs of Friends and their Family n.d. (Box-folder 81:18)
  - Scrapbook, photos of University of Virginia n.d. (Box-folder 81:19)
  - Post cards n.d. (Box-folder 81:20)
    re; Richmond and Nashville
  - Program of Dedication Ceremonies of The Jefferson Davis Memorial at Vicksburg n.d. (Box-folder 81:21)
  - Poems 81:22 (Box-folder 81:22)
  - Correspondence between John Randolph of Roanoke and his cousin Nancy, presented to Collins Denny by E. C. Reeves n.d. (Box-folder 81:23)
- Collins Denny Collection: Subdivided topically into Methodist Collection; Civil War and Reconstruction; and Miscellaneous
  - Methodism; Sources n.d. (Box-folder 82:1)
    re: History of Methodist ritual and discipline
  - Chronology of elders, Berkley 1778-1835 (Box-folder 82:2)
  - "Minutes of the Methodist Conference from the first.. ." n.d. (Box-folder 82:3)
  - Methodism: Methodist Discipline of 1784 1784 (Box-folder 82:4)
  - A file of 18th. Century Methodist Discipline n.d. (Box-folder 82:5)
  - Methodism: Members General Conference 1808 (Box-folder 82:6)
  - Methodism: Letters, Speeches, etc. of William McKendrice 1818-1833 (Box-folder 82:7)
  - Methodism: Letter of Member General Conference 1844, copy (Box-folder 82:8)
  - Methodism: Photo of meeting place of First General Conference 1846 (Box-folder 82:9)
  - Methodism: Plan of appointments 1853-1854 (Box-folder 82:10)
  - Pastoral address of the Southern Methodist Bishops 1865 (Box-folder 82:11)
  - Methodism: J. S. Martin Pastoral address 1866 (Box-folder 82:12)
  - Methodism: Church Property Question, Holston 1869 (Box-folder 82:13)
  - Methodism: Program of General Conference 1884 (Box-folder 82:14)
  - Notes, programs n.d. (Box-folder 82:15)
    re: General Conference of 1894
  - S. A. Steel case, accusation and decision 1896 (Box-folder 82:16)
  - Methodism: The "Old Russell House" 1896 (Box-folder 82:17)
  - Methodism: "The Passage of Dr. Barbee's Character" by J. J. Ransom 1899 (Box-folder 82:18)
  - Literature from General Conference 1906 (Box-folder 82:20)
  - Minutes and reports of investigation; W. G. Fletcher Case 1906-1916 (Box-folder 82:21)
  - Ecumenical Conference Delegate List 1911 October (Box-folder 82:22)
  - "Revivial Notes" by Geo. H. Wiley 1912 (Box-folder 82:23)
  - Weekly and Annual Report Forms 1912 and n.d. (Box-folder 82:24)
  - Minutes of Methodist Conference 1912 September-1914 March (Box-folder 82:25)
  - "First of All Save Men" by Bishop A. W. Wilson 1914 (Box-folder 82:26)
  - Literature on Doctrinal Controversy in Y. W. C. A. [1914?]- 1918 (Box-folder 82:27)
  - Protest literature 1916 (Box-folder 82:28)